Previously, in Camille's adventures:
Every day Camille uses some application
on her smartphone,
but she discovered the existence of trackers,
those little pieces of code
which collect informations about her.
Camille asks her self
how those trackers came into the applications?
An Exodus Privacy video
In order to answer this question,
Camille must understand
how applications are made.
An application is a little bit like a car.
They are both complex to build.
A lot of work
Developers,
the persons who write code in computer language
could choose to use an already done piece of code
from code libraries
or write all the application code from scratch.
Ok. So when did the trackers come into the applications?
A tracker is a piece of code.
So someone has written it at one time
into the application program.
It could come form the persons who wrote the applications,
for example if their income comes from advertising.
But sometimes this people do not even know they add tracker.
For example, if a developer uses a piece of code written by others
which uses geolocation whitout her knowledge,
and the final application will have a tracker.
And if Camille installs it on her smartphone,
she will be tracked through this.
As we can find the same engine in differents cars,
we can find same trackers in many applications.
To keep an eye on Camille's adventure,
you can watch the first two episodes
and subscribe to the Exodus Privacys YouTube Channel,
or find them on Peertube.
Follow us on Mastodon, Twitter or Facebook.